I want to talk about rival ristmas
and anti rival resinous during this time
period it is imperative that we focus on
anti rivalries and nonrival resolutions
because they're what is going to get us
through but our entire society and our
personal selves are conditioned to
create rival resolutions ones where I
win and you lose or you win and I lose
and those aren't going to get us through
and so I'm going to go through a few
categories and what a rival resolution
would look like versus been downright
low resolution in this time or an anti
Bible resolution auntie brotherly
rivalry solution I wish there was a
better name is a solution that the more
people are involved in it the better it
is as opposed to win lose it's when more
people come the more we all win and it
grows exponentially which here all are
gonna be learned in some exponential
math over the lap next few weeks and
months that is horrific
and this will be some exponential good
news as more people join and we have
more capacity to do more and more good
in this world so food food under the
rival risk category looks very much like
14 it's what we're currently doing look
you know for your own making sure you
have enough food to come through not
just the two weeks or months quarantine
but also the possible impending food
crisis that's coming down the line of
course there's a lot of issues with that
there's not enough for everyone then
people who don't have a lot of money you
go to the stores and there's enough food
but more than that when you think about
down the line even if you have a
stockpile of food if other people are
hungry and other people are starving
there's going to be violence and so what
is an anti Rifle rest solution look like
for food it looks like us coordinating
now looking what happened six months a
year down the road how do we get labor
to the farms to get the food out of the
field how do we do guerilla gardening
now how are we using every city
Boulevard
every green space to be growing food for
the masses how do we coordinate the time
how do we how do we deal with with those
things those are non rival risks and to
rival order solutions we need to feed
our cities
we need to do so especially in Canada
with the understood the hypothesis that
the states will not be sending food to
us we will not be buying food from them
as they go through their own their own
issues we have to grow enough for
ourselves what does finances look like
in a rivalry situation is looking for
opportunities to get rich right now and
even and none of these rival respons are
necessarily bad in and of themselves
this is what we're used to but at the
same time if what you're looking for is
how to feed your family how to keep rent
in your mortgage paid at it's always
been at the expense of others but now
even more so we're in this together and
so what does Finance look like in a anti
rivalry situation it's knowing we're in
this together knowing that if you can't
pay your mortgage and you can't pay your
rent neither can anyone else and we can
find solutions that work we can go on
rent and mortgage strike we can have a
debt Jubilee we can make sure everyone
is taken care of or we can pressure our
governments to pass ubi and have her
front rent and mortgage freeze but to
focus on that we are in it together and
we have powers together the virus itself
thinking about me me me me me I'm in the
young category I can I can survive this
no problem or this is really
inconvenient I'm not getting to go to
all of my my travelling expenses again
totally valid you get to have your
emotions you get to do grieve what you
thought the world was and what the world
was was coming in what your life looked
like in the coming weeks and months and
people are going through real-life
events right now people are still having
cancer and still having to deal with
that people are giving birth people are
losing loved ones to this virus and
other things they're not being able to
hold funerals on have you able to have
birthday parties there are real things
happening right now that are absolutely
valid but the more we focus on how is
this impacted me and poor me the less
we're going to be able to focus on the
anti rivalry side which is how do we get
through this virus the actual biological
enemy and it's with crowdsourcing how do
we how do we help our frontline workers
both within the metal community and the
bigger surrounding community right our
grocery store workers the gas station it
how can we make sure that their lives
are easier and I think it's by asking
what would make your life easier a lot
of the solutions aren't necessarily
gonna be there I don't know can we go in
and clean our nurses and doctors houses
without further risking ourselves yes
there were people who this is a lower
risk for and people who have already had
it but they could be going in and doing
those things we can be making food for
them doing it in a safe way doing their
grocery shopping for them anything
that's gonna make their life easier
because they're concentrated 24/7 on
community health how do we help them run
their families and their households and
reduce their stress to the lowest
possible that it's kind of that it's
possible to be under these very
high-stress situations how do we open
crowd-sourced science so that we can
share information as as laymen as people
who are just you know maybe you don't
understand science how do we understand
how do we get information we can trust
and use and not all of the by our other
viral technologically viral messages
that are going around that are fake and
wrong and are just not trustworthy and
how do we know what is trustworthy and
then how do we create a system for the
experts just to coordinate so that we
can get a vaccine sooner so that we can
get treatment options so that not just
for this pandemic but for anyone that's
coming down the pipeline how can we get
the experts to coordinate so it's not
for the normal profit rival risk
situation I want to be the one to decide
it discovers this so that so that I can
make the money or I can have the
prestige and instead how do we get this
done the fastest how do we get the best
information to the most people then how
do we ramp up the production of vaccines
how do we ramp up the production of
masks and productive equipment right now
and testing gear we there is so much to
do and while our medical team that
people are concentrating on that on the
virus itself other ones of us can
concentrate our energy is needed on the
food production on mental health on how
we emerge into a world that is beautiful
and abundant a world we want to live in
this virus is showing us how
interconnected we are how it doesn't
just impact me because I feel sad that
my neighbors poor it actually affects my
life they're gonna be more likely to go
and spread the buyers because they have
to work they're gonna be more likely to
go out and spread the virus because they
can't afford medical the counterparts go
to their doctor that's not here in
Canada but definitely the United States
the people who don't have money have to
make different decisions even if they're
not in your best interests that people
who are scared and not trusting in the
media cost us all and the media has been
a big reason that happens they've been
crying wolf for years over every little
thing blowing everything out of
proportion at now that there's something
that we actually need them to trust and
listen to they and they're they don't
they're in fear and so we need to be
able to create the systems that help
everyone and ask if you're not doing
what we what you're what we want you to
do ie stand inside
why aren't you what would help you do
that and create the systems to actually
help them do it how do we help you
maintain quarantine how do we help you
have social distancing without it
drastically impacting your finances and
your mental health and it's by finding
out how we do this together how we come
up with anti rival resolutions to the
coming weeks and months and years thank
you